You should consider yourself lucky.
你应该觉得自己很幸运。
At least your balls won't freeze off.
至少你的蛋蛋不会冻坏。
You take great offense at dwarf jokes,
but love telling eunuch jokes.
你对矮人的笑话很生气，
但我喜欢讲太监的笑话。
Why is that?
为什么呢？
Because I have balls, and you don't.
因为我有胆，而你没有。
I warned you.
我警告过你。
Northerners don't much trust
outsiders.
北方人不太信任别人
局外人。
Man: May the gods protect us!
男：愿神保佑我们！
Look at you.
看看你。
You're a man.
你是个男人。
Almost.
几乎。
- Jon: Where's Arya?
- Lurking somewhere.
Arya在哪儿？
-潜伏在某处。
Jon: Queen Daenerys
of house Targaryen.
琼恩：丹妮莉丝女王
坦格利安家族的人
My sister, sansa stark,
the lady of winterfell.
我妹妹珊莎·史塔克
临冬城的夫人。
Thank you for inviting us
into your home, lady stark.
谢谢你邀请我们
去你家，史塔克夫人。
The north is as beautiful
as your brother claimed,
北方同样美丽
正如你哥哥所说
as are you.
你也是。
Winterfell is yours, your grace.
临冬城是您的了，陛下。
We don't have time for all this.
我们没时间说这些了。
The night king has your dragon.
He's one of them now.
夜王拿了你的龙。
他现在是他们中的一员。
The wall has fallen,
the dead march south.
墙倒了，
死者向南行进。
Sansa: As soon as we heard
about the wall,
珊莎：我们一听说
关于墙，
I called all our banners
to retreat to winterfell.
我打电话给我们所有的横幅
撤退到临冬城。
Lord umber...
主棕土……
When can we expect
your people to arrive?
我们什么时候可以
你的人会来吗？
We need more horses and wagons,
if it please my lady.
我们需要更多的马和马车，
如果您愿意的话，夫人。
And my lord.
我的大人。
And my queen.
还有我的王后。
Sorry.
对不起。
Sansa: You'll have
as many as we can spare.
珊莎：你会的
尽可能多的人。
Hurry back to last hearth
and bring your people here.
赶快回到最后的壁炉
把你的人带来。
We need to send ravens
to the night's watch as well.
我们得派乌鸦去
还有守夜人。
There's no sense
in Manning the castles anymore.
没有意义
管理城堡的事
We make our stand here.
我们在这里立下阵地。
At once, your grace.
马上，陛下。
"Your grace."
“你的恩典。”
But you're not. Are you?
但你不是。是吗?
You left winterfell a king
and came back a...
你以国王的身份离开临冬城
回来的时候…
I'm not sure what you are now.
我不知道你现在是什么。
A lord?
主吗?
Nothing at all?
什么都没有？
- It's not important.
- Lady mormont: Not important?
-这不重要。
不重要？
We named you king in the north.
我们选你为北境之王。
Man: King in the north!
男：北方之王万岁！
You did, my lady.
是的，夫人。
It was the honor of my life.
这是我一生的荣幸。
I'll always be grateful
for your faith.
我将永远心存感激
为了你的信仰。
But when I left winterfell, I told you
we need allies or we will die.
但当我离开临冬城时，我告诉过你
我们需要盟友，否则我们会死。
I have brought those allies home
to fight alongside us.
我已经把那些盟友带回家了
和我们并肩作战。
I had a choice,
我有一个选择
keep my crown or protect the north.
要么保住王冠，要么保护北境。
I chose the north.
我选择了北方。
If anyone survives the war to come,
we'll have Jon snow to thank.
如果有人能在即将到来的战争中幸存
我们得感谢琼恩·雪诺。
He risked his life
to show us the threat is real.
他冒着生命危险
让我们知道威胁是真的。
Thanks to his courage,
由于他的勇气，
we have brought with us the greatest
army the world has ever seen.
我们带来了最伟大的
世界上最伟大的军队。
We have brought
two full-grown dragons.
我们带来了
两条成熟的龙。
And soon, the Lannister army
will ride north to join our cause.
很快，兰尼斯特的军队
会北上加入我们的事业。
I know, I know, our people
haven't been friends in the past.
我知道，我知道，我们的人
我们以前不是朋友。
But we must fight together now...
但我们现在必须一起战斗……
Or die.
或死亡。
May I ask, how are we meant to feed
我能问一下，我们要怎么养活自己
the greatest army
the world has ever seen?
最伟大的军队
世界上见过的？
While I ensured our stores
would last through winter,
当我确保我们的商店
将持续整个冬天，
I didn't account for Dothraki,
unsullied and two full-grown dragons.
我没有考虑到多斯拉克人
无垢者和两条成年龙。
What do dragons eat, anyway?
龙到底吃什么？
Whatever they want.
他们想要什么都行。
Hey, careful, lads.
We need every last bit of it.
小心点，伙计们。
我们需要每一分钱。
Man 1: Sorry 'bout that.
男士1：很抱歉。
Are these the last of the wagons?
这些是最后一批马车吗？
Man 2: Aye.
男2：是啊。
Gendry: All right,
let's get it all to the forges.
詹德利：好吧，
我们把它们都运到锻造厂吧。
My lord.
我的主。
My lady.
我的夫人。
The lady of winterfell.
临冬城的夫人。
Has a nice ring to it.
听起来很好听。
So does hand of the queen.
王后之手也是。
Depending on the queen, I suppose.
我想这取决于女王。
Last time we spoke
was at Joffrey's wedding.
上次我们谈话时
乔佛里的婚礼
- Miserable affair.
- It had its moments.
-悲惨的事。
-它有它的时刻。
Apologies for leaving like that.
很抱歉我就那样走了。
Yes, it was a bit hard to explain
是的，这有点难以解释
why my wife fled
moments after the king's murder.
为什么我的妻子逃走了
国王被谋杀后不久。
We both survived.
我们都活了下来。
Many underestimated you.
很多人低估了你。
Most of them are dead now.
他们大多数人现在都死了。
I'm sure you weren't thrilled to hear
the Lannister army's marching north.
我相信你听了肯定不高兴
兰尼斯特的军队正在北上
You have every right
to be fearful of my sister.
你完全有权利
害怕我的妹妹。
No one fears her more than I do.
But I promise, you'll be safe...
没人比我更怕她。
但我保证，你会很安全的……
Cersei told you her army
was coming north to fight for you?
瑟曦告诉过你她的军队
是来北方为你战斗的吗？
She did.
她做到了。
And you believed her?
你相信她？
She has something to live for now.
I believe she wants to survive.
她现在有活下去的理由了。
我相信她想活下去。
I used to think
you were the cleverest man alive.
我曾经以为
你是世上最聪明的人。
Arya: You used to be taller.
艾莉亚：你以前更高。
Jon: How did you sneak up on me?
乔恩：你是怎么偷偷接近我的？
How did you survive
a knife through the heart?
你是怎么活下来的？
一刀穿心？
I didn't.
我没有。
You still have it.
你还留着它。
Needle.
针。
Have you ever used it?
你用过吗？
Once or twice.
一两次。
Valyrian steel.
Valyrian钢。
Jealous?
嫉妒?
Too heavy for me.
对我来说太重了。
Where were you before?
你以前在哪里？
I could've used your help with sansa.
我本可以让你帮我搞定珊莎的。
She doesn't like your queen,
does she?
她不喜欢你的女王
是吗?
Sansa thinks
she's smarter than everyone.
珊莎认为
她比谁都聪明。
She's the smartest person
I've ever met.
她是最聪明的人
我见过的最好的人。
Now you're defending her?
现在你在为她辩护？
You?
你吗?
I'm defending our family.
我在保护我们的家庭。
So is she.
她也是。
Yeah.
是的。
I'm her family too.
我也是她的家人。
Don't forget that.
别忘了这一点。
Your grace,
I'm afraid I bring terrible news.
你的恩典,
恐怕我带来了坏消息。
The dead have
broken through the wall.
死去的人
穿墙而过。
Good.
好。
Why don't you just get it over with
and kill me?
你为什么不快点结束呢
然后杀了我？
But we're family.
但我们是一家人。
The last greyjoys left in the world.
世上仅存的葛雷乔伊家族。
The last ones with balls anyway.
反正是最后一个有蛋蛋的。
If I kill you...
如果我杀了你…
Who can I talk to?
我可以和谁通话？
I've got a crew full of mutes.
我手下全是哑巴。
It gets lonely at sea.
在海上很寂寞。
Are we in king's landing?
我们是在君临吗？
Euron: Mmm.
Euron:嗯。
You picked the losing side.
你选择了失败的一方。
Then I'll sail the iron fleet
somewhere else.
然后我将驾驶铁舰队
别的地方。
But first I'm gonna fuck the queen.
但首先我要操皇后。
Cersei: Twenty-thousand men, is it?
瑟曦：两万人，是吗？
Yes, your grace.
A few died in transit.
是的，陛下。
一些人在运输途中死亡。
They cheated at dice.
他们掷骰子作弊。
Or maybe I cheated.
或者我作弊了。
Someone cheated.
有人被骗了。
They weren't good fighters.
You won't miss them.
他们不是优秀的战士。
你不会错过的。
- Horses?
- Two thousand.
——马?
-两千。
And elephants?
和大象吗?
Strickland:
Uh, no elephants, your grace.
斯特里克兰:
陛下，不要大象。
That's disappointing.
这是令人失望的。
I was told
the golden company had elephants.
有人告诉我
黄金公司有大象。
Strickland: They are excellent beasts,
your grace,
思特里克兰德：它们都是优秀的动物。
你的恩典,
but not well-suited
to long sea voyages.
但并不适合
长途海上航行。
In any event, you are most welcome
无论如何，你是最受欢迎的
here in king's landing,
captain strickland.
在君临，
斯特里克兰船长。
We look foward to fighting
on your behalf, your grace.
我们期待战斗
我代表您，陛下。
Euron: Am I most welcome here?
攸伦：这里欢迎我吗？
You are a true friend of the crown
and an honored guest.
你是王室真正的朋友
也是一位贵宾。
Euron: Good.
Euron:很好。
As a true friend
and an honored guest...
作为一个真正的朋友
还有一位贵宾……
I was hoping
we could talk in private.
我希望
我们可以私下谈谈。
After the war.
That was our agreement.
战后。
这是我们的协议。
Wars sometimes last years.
战争有时会持续数年。
You want a whore, buy one.
你想要妓女，那就买一个。
You want a queen...
你想要一个女王……
Earn her.
获得她的。
How?
如何?
I've given herjustice, an army
and the iron fleet,
我给了她正义，一支军队
还有钢铁舰队，
yet she gives me
no sign of affection.
然而她给了我
没有感情的迹象。
My heart is nearly broken.
我的心都快碎了。
You're insolent.
你是傲慢的。
- I've executed men for less.
- They were lesser men.
-我也以更少的罪名处决过犯人。
-他们是下等人。
Dirah: I hear the dragon burnt up
a thousand Lannister men.
狄拉：我听说龙被烧死了
一千名兰尼斯特人。
Craya: Burnt up
some of my favorite boys.
克雷亚：烧焦了
一些我最喜欢的男孩。
- Dirah: Archie, was it?
- And William.
Archie，是吗？
-还有威廉。
- Tall handsome William?
- Yeah, tall handsome William.
-又高又帅的威廉？
-对，又高又帅的威廉。
They said what's left of him
could fit in a wine glass.
他们说了他的遗骨
可以装进一个酒杯。
I am the only man you ever met
who shot a dragon.
我是你见过的唯一的男人
谁射了一条龙。
- Did you?
- Bronn: Nearly killed it.
-是吗？
差点杀了它。
That's brave.
这是勇敢的。
Craya: That boy Eddie...
Dirah: The ginger?
克蕾亚：那个男孩埃迪……
迪拉：姜？
That's him. Came back
with his face burnt right off.
这是他。回来
他的脸被烧掉了。
He's got no eyelids now.
他现在没有眼睑了。
How does he sleep with no eyelids?
他没有眼皮怎么睡得着？
All right, can we stop talking
about the fucking dragons now?
好了，我们能别说了吗
那该死的龙呢？
Qyburn: Ser bronn of the Blackwater.
奎伯恩：黑水河的波隆爵士。
You're kidding me.
你在开玩笑吧。
Apologies for the interruption,
but the queen did urge me to hurry.
抱歉打扰了，
但王后催促我快点。
Sorry, ladies.
对不起,女士。
Another time perhaps.
也许下次吧。
You ever get lonely,
I am partial to older gentlemen.
你是否感到孤独，
我偏爱年长的绅士。
Poor girl. The pox will take her
within the year.
可怜的女孩。瘟疫会带走她的
在一年内。
- Which girl?
- Qyburn: The queen's brothers
-哪个女孩？
女王的兄弟们
made promises to you and broke them.
对你许下承诺却又食言。
Her grace wants to rectify
their mistake.
女王陛下想改过自新
他们的错误。
She once gave me a castle and a wife,
then rectified me right out of them.
她曾经给过我一座城堡和一个妻子，
然后纠正了我的错误。
That was ser Jaime's doing, not hers.
那是詹姆爵士的事，不是她的。
When queen Cersei wants something,
she pays in advance and in gold.
当瑟曦王后想要什么，
她预付金子。
Several chests of it, in fact.
事实上，有好几个箱子。
Waiting for you
in a wagon just outside.
等着你
就在外面的马车里。
So she wants to murder someone,
but she can't send her soldiers.
所以她想谋杀某人
但她不能派遣她的士兵。
If it's the dragon queen
she's after...
如果是龙后的话
后,她的……
She has other plans
for the Targaryen girl.
她另有打算
坦格利安家的女孩。
Yeah, well, good luck with that.
好吧，祝你好运。
Our queen's brothers are unlikely
to survive their northern adventures.
我们女王的兄弟不太可能
在北方探险中幸存下来
But in the event that they do...
但万一他们真的这么做了…
She has a keen sense
of poetic justice.
她有敏锐的感觉
诗意的正义。
That fucking family.
那个该死的家庭。
Qyburn: When the citadel expelled me,
I thought I would die poor and alone,
当城堡驱逐我的时候，
我以为我会孤苦伶仃地死去，
but in exchange for my service,
queen Cersei made me her hand.
但作为我服务的交换，
瑟曦王后让我做她的手。
What would she do for the man who
rids her of her treasonous brothers?
她会为一个男人做什么
让她摆脱那些叛国的兄弟？
I wanted those elephants.
我想要那些大象。
Euron: So...
Euron:所以…
How do I compare to the fat king?
我和胖王比起来怎么样？
You're insulting my late husband?
你在侮辱我已故的丈夫？
Are you offended?
你被冒犯了吗？
Robert had a different whore
every night,
劳勃有另一个妓女
每天晚上,
but he still didn't know
his way around a woman's body.
但他仍然不知道
他玩弄女人的身体。
And the kingslayer?
那么弑君者呢？
You enjoy risking your neck,
dontyou?
你喜欢冒着生命危险
dontyou吗?
Life is boring.
生活很无聊。
You're not boring,
I'll give you that.
你不无聊，
我承认。
Do I please the queen?
我能取悦女王吗？
You might be the most arrogant man
I've ever met.
你可能是最傲慢的人
我见过的最好的人。
I like that.
我喜欢这样。
But now I want to be alone.
但现在我想一个人待着。
I'm going to put
a prince in your belly.
我要把
你肚子里有个王子。
Yara: Euron can't defend
the iron islands,
雅拉：攸伦无法防守
铁群岛，
not if he's in king's landing
with all his men and his ships.
只要他在君临就不会
带着他所有的人和船。
We can take our home back.
我们可以夺回我们的家。
Daenerys went north.
丹妮莉丝向北走去。
Daenerys will need somewhere to
retreat if they can't hold the north.
丹妮莉丝需要找个地方
如果守不住北面就撤退。
Somewhere the dead can't go.
一个死人去不了的地方。
You're my queen.
I go where you command.
你是我的女王。
我到你吩咐的地方去。
You want to go to winterfell.
你想去临冬城。
To fight for the starks.
为史塔克家族而战。
What is dead may never die.
死的东西可能永远不会死。
But kill the bastards anyway.
但还是要杀了那些混蛋。
Wolkan: Welcome back, my lady.
欢迎回来，夫人。
If you'd follow me...
请跟我来……
Varys: The karstarks.
瓦里斯：卡史塔克家族。
Tyrion: One of the better sigils.
提利昂：最好的徽章之一。
Beats an onion, anyway.
反正比洋葱强。
Can't argue with that.
这是无可争辩的。
Not so long ago,
the starks and the karstarks
不久前，
stark和karstarks
were slaughtering each other
on the battlefield.
我们互相残杀吗
在战场上。
Jon snow brought peace to the houses.
琼恩·雪诺为家族带来了和平。
Tyrion: And our queen is grateful.
提利昂：我们的女王很感激。
Her gratitude is lovely,
but that's not my point.
她的感激是可爱的，
但这不是我的重点。
The northmen are loyal to Jon snow,
not to her.
北方人忠于琼恩·雪诺
对她来说不是。
They don't know her.
他们不认识她。
The free folk don't know her.
自由民不认识她。
I've been up here a while,
and I'm telling you,
我在这里待了一段时间
我告诉你
they're stubborn as goats.
他们像山羊一样固执。
You want their loyalty,
you have to earn it.
你想要他们的忠诚
你必须去争取。
I sense that you're leading
to a proposal.
我感觉你在领导
一个提议。
A proposal is what I'm proposing.
我的提议就是求婚。
On the off chance
that we survive the night king,
以极小的机会
我们逃过夜王的魔爪
what if the seven kingdoms,
for once in their whole shit history,
如果七大王国
这是他们历史上第一次，
were ruled by a just woman
and an honorable man?
被一个公正的女人统治
一个正直的人？
Tyrion: They do make
a handsome couple.
提利昂：的确
一对英俊的夫妇。
Varys: You overestimate our influence.
瓦里斯：你高估了我们的影响力。
Jon and Daenerys don't want to listen
to lonely old men.
琼恩和丹妮莉丝不想听
给孤独的老人。
I'm not that old.
我没那么老。
Not as old as him.
没有他那么老。
Our queen respects the wisdom of age.
我们的女王尊重长者的智慧。
Of course she does.
她当然知道。
Respect is how the young
keep us at a distance,
尊重是如何年轻的
让我们保持距离
so we don't remind them
of an unpleasant truth.
所以我们不提醒他们
一个令人不快的事实。
Tyrion: What is that?
提利昂：那是什么？
Nothing lasts.
没有什么永恒的东西。
Man: Hey!
男:嘿!
Your sister doesn't like me.
你姐姐不喜欢我。
She doesn't know you.
她不认识你。
If it makes you feel better,
如果这能让你好受点，
she didn't like me either
when we were growing up.
她也不喜欢我
当我们长大的时候。
She doesn't need to be my friend...
她不需要成为我的朋友……
But I am her queen.
但我是她的女王。
If she can't respect me...
如果她不尊重我…
How many today?
今天有多少？
Only eighteen goats and eleven sheep.
只有十八只山羊和十一只绵羊。
What's the matter?
怎么了？
The dragons are barely eating.
龙几乎不吃东西。
Jon: What's wrong with them?
乔恩：它们怎么了？
They don't like the north.
他们不喜欢北方。
Go on.
继续。
I don't know how to ride a dragon.
我不知道怎么骑龙。
Nobody does.
Until they ride a dragon.
没有人做。
直到他们骑上一条龙。
What if he doesn't want me to?
如果他不想让我去呢？
Then I've enjoyed your company,
Jon snow.
那我很喜欢你的陪伴
琼恩雪诺。
What do I hold onto?
我该坚持什么？
Whatever you can.
尽你所能。
Jon: Aah!
乔恩:啊!
You've completely
ruined horses for me.
你已经完全
毁了我的马。
We could stay a thousand years...
我们可以待上一千年……
No one would find us.
没人会找到我们的。
We'd be pretty old.
我们会很老的。
It's cold up here
for a southern girl.
这里很冷
对一个南方女孩来说。
So keep your queen warm.
所以让你的女王保持温暖。
Don't be afraid.
不要害怕。
Man 1: That's good.
男1：那很好。
Man 2: Gendry? Man 3: He's here.
男2：詹德利？男人3：他在这里。
It isn't easy making a blade that big
with dragonglass.
做这么大的刀片可不容易
dragonglass。
You're saying you're good,
is that it?
你说你很好，
就是这样吗？
I'm just saying
it's a tricky material to...
我只是说
这是一种棘手的材料……
You know who makes weapons
for the wildlings?
你知道谁制造武器
为了野人？
Cripples and cocksuckers.
瘸子和鸡巴。
Which one are you?
你是哪一个？
Arya: Leave him be.
艾莉亚：别管他。
I heard you were here.
我听说你在这里。
You left me to die.
你让我等死。
First I robbed you.
首先我抢劫了你。
You're a cold little bitch,
aren't you?
你是个冷酷的小贱人
不是吗?
Guess that's why you're still alive.
我猜这就是你还活着的原因。
That was a nice ax you made for him.
你给他做的斧头真不错。
You've gotten better.
你已经好多了。
Yeah, thanks. So have you.
是的,谢谢。你也是。
I mean, you look good.
我是说，你看起来不错。
Thanks. So do you.
谢谢。你也是。
It's not a bad place to grow up,
if it wasn't so cold.
这是个适合长大的地方，
如果不是这么冷的话。
Stay close to that forge, then.
那就待在铁匠铺附近。
Oh, is that a command, lady stark?
史塔克夫人，这是命令吗？
Don't call me that.
别那么叫我。
As you wish, milady.
如你所愿，夫人。
Arya: Here's my wish.
艾莉亚：这是我的愿望。
Can you make it?
你能来吗？
What do you need
something like this for?
你需要什么？
像这样的东西有什么用？
Can you make it or not?
你到底能不能做到？
You already have a sword.
你已经有一把剑了。
What's that?
那是什么?
It's valyrian steel.
这是瓦雷利亚钢。
I always knew
you were just another rich girl.
我一直都知道
你只是另一个富家女。
You don't know any other rich girls.
你不认识别的富家女。
Come in.
进来。
Lord glover wishes us good fortune,
格洛弗勋爵祝我们好运，
but he's staying in deepwood motte
with his men.
但他现在住在深木堡
和他的人。
"House glover will stand
behind house stark
“房子的手套将会站立
在房子后面
as we have for a thousand years."
就像我们一千年来一样。”
Isn't that what he said?
他不是这么说的吗？
Sansa: "I will stand
behind Jon snow," he said.
珊莎：“我要站起来
在琼恩·雪诺身后，”他说。
"The king in the north."
“北境之王。”
- I told you we needed allies.
- Sansa: You didn't tell me
-我说过我们需要盟友。
你没告诉我
you were going to abandon your crown.
你要放弃你的王冠。
I never wanted a crown.
我从来不想要王冠。
All I wanted
was to protect the north.
我想要的一切
是为了保护北方
I brought two armies home with me,
two dragons.
我带了两支军队回家，
两龙。
And a Targaryen queen.
还有坦格利安女王。
Do you think we can beat
the army of the dead without her?
你觉得我们能赢吗
没有她的死亡大军？
I fought them, sansa. Twice.
珊莎，我跟他们打过仗。两次。
You want to worry about
who holds what title,
你想要担心的
谁拥有什么头衔，
I'm telling you it doesn't matter.
我告诉你，这无关紧要。
Without her, we don't stand a chance.
没有她，我们一点机会都没有。
Do you have any faith in me at all?
你对我还有信心吗？
You know I do.
你知道的。
She'll be a good queen.
她会是个好王后。
For all of us.
为了我们所有人。
She's not her father.
她不是她爸爸。
No, she's much prettier.
不，她漂亮多了。
Did you bend the knee to save
the north or because you love her?
你屈膝救人了吗
去北方还是因为你爱她？
Oh!
哦!
So you're the man?
你就是那个男人？
Which man am I, your grace?
陛下，我是谁？
The one who saved ser jorah
when no one else could.
救了乔拉爵士的人
没人能做到。
They could, they just wouldn't.
他们可以，他们就是不愿意。
Daenerys: I'll have to
make some changes
丹妮莉丝：我必须这么做
做一些改变
in the citadel when I take my throne.
当我登基的时候
A great service
merits a great reward.
很棒的服务
值得奖赏。
Samwell: Oh, it's my honor
to serve you, your grace.
山姆威尔：哦，这是我的荣幸
为您效劳，陛下。
Daenerys: Well, there must be
something I could give you.
丹妮莉丝：嗯，肯定有
我可以给你一些东西。
If it's not too much trouble,
I could use a pardon.
如果不太麻烦的话，
我可以请求原谅。
For what crime?
犯了什么罪？
I borrowed a few books
from the citadel.
我借了几本书
从城堡里。
And also a sword.
还有一把剑。
- From the citadel?
- Samwell: From my family.
-从城堡来的？
我家的。
It's been in house tarly
for generations.
很早就在家里了
好几代了。
It would've been mine
anyway, eventually,
本来是我的
不管怎么说,最终,
but my father had other ideas.
但是我父亲有其他的想法。
Not randyll tarly?
不是兰德尔·塔利吗？
You know him?
你认识他？
I offered to let him retain his lands
and titles if he bent the knee.
我提出让他保留他的土地
如果他下跪，还有头衔。
He refused.
他拒绝了。
Well...
嗯…
At least I'll be allowed home again,
now that my brother's the lord.
至少我又可以回家了，
现在我哥哥是领主了。
Your brother stood with your father.
你哥哥和你父亲站在一起。
Hmm.
嗯。
Thank you, your grace.
谢谢您，陛下。
For telling me.
谢谢你告诉我。
And m...
和m…
- May I...?
- Of course.
-我可以…吗？
-当然。
What are you doing out here?
你在外面干什么？
Waiting, for an old friend.
等待，等待一个老朋友。
It's time to tell Jon the truth.
是时候告诉琼恩真相了。
No, no.
不,不。
You're his brother.
Shouldn't you tell him?
你是他的兄弟。
你不应该告诉他吗？
I'm not his brother.
我不是他的兄弟。
He trusts you more than anyone.
他比任何人都信任你。
Now's the time.
现在是时候了。
Jon: Sam?
乔恩:山姆?
I'm sorry, I know
I'm not supposed to be down here.
对不起，我知道
我不该来这里的。
Were you hiding from me?
你在躲着我吗？
Of course not.
当然不是。
What are you doing in winterfell?
你来临冬城干什么？
Or did you read every book
in the citadel already?
还是你读了每一本书
已经在城堡里了？
What's wrong?
怎么了?
Gilly? Is she all right?
侍从?她还好吗？
- She's good.
- Little Sam?
-她很好。
-小萨姆？
Don't you know?
你不知道吗？
Know what?
知道吗?
Daenerys...
Daenerys……
She executed my father and brother.
她处决了我的父亲和哥哥。
They were her prisoners.
他们是她的俘虏。
She didn't tell you.
她没告诉你。
I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉。
We need to end this war.
我们需要结束这场战争。
Would you have done it?
你会这么做吗？
Well, I've executed men
who disobeyed me.
我处决过犯人
谁不听我的话。
You've also spared men.
你也宽恕了男人。
Thousands ofwildlings
when they refused to kneel.
数千ofwildlings
当他们拒绝下跪。
I wasn't a king.
我不是国王。
But you were.
但你确实是。
You've always been.
你一直都是。
I gave up my crown, Sam.
我放弃了我的王冠，山姆。
I bent the knee.
I'm not king in the north anymore.
我弯下膝盖。
我不再是北境之王了。
I'm not talking about
the king in the north.
我说的不是
北方的国王。
I'm talking about the king
of the bloody seven kingdoms.
我说的是国王
七国之王。
Bran and I worked it out.
布兰和我解决了。
I had a high septon's diary.
Bran had...
我有一本大主教的日记。
糠了……
Whatever bran has.
不管麸皮有什么。
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
Your mother...
你的母亲……
Was lyanna stark.
是莱安娜·史塔克。
Samwell: And your father...
山姆威尔：还有你父亲……
Your real father
你的亲生父亲
was rhaegar Targaryen.
是雷加·坦格利安。
You've never been a bastard.
你从来就不是私生子。
You're aegon Targaryen,
true heir to the iron throne.
你是伊耿·坦格利安，
铁王座的真正继承人
I'm sorry,
I know it's a lot to take in.
我很抱歉,
我知道你一时难以接受。
My father was the most honorable man
I ever met.
我父亲是最可敬的人
我见过的最好的人。
You're saying
he lied to me all my life.
你说的
他骗了我一辈子。
Your father... well, ned stark.
你的父亲……奈德·史塔克。
He promised your mother
he'd always protect you.
他答应过你母亲
他会一直保护你。
And he did. Robert would have
murdered you if he knew.
他做到了。罗伯特会
如果他知道了就杀了你。
You're the true king.
你才是真正的国王。
Aegon Targaryen, sixth of his name,
protector of the realm, all of it.
伊耿·坦格利安六世
王国的守护者，所有的一切。
- Daenerys is our queen.
- Samwell: She shouldn't be.
-丹妮莉丝是我们的女王。
她不应该这样。
- That's treason.
- It's the truth.
-那是叛国。
-这是事实。
You gave up your crown
to save your people.
你放弃了你的王冠
为了拯救你的人民。
Would she do the same?
她也会这么做吗？
Stay back, he's got blue eyes!
退后，他有蓝眼睛！
I've always had blue eyes!
我的眼睛一直是蓝的！
Did you find anyone?
你找到人了吗？
Dolorous edd: The umber boy.
忧郁的艾迪：数字男孩。
Beric: It's a message.
Beric：这是一个信息。
From the night king.
夜王送来的。
His army's between us and winterfell.
We're on foot.
他的军队挡在我们和临冬城之间。
我们步行。
We rode down from castle black.
我们从黑城堡骑下来。
We can double up on the horses.
我们可以加倍下注。
If the horses last,
we'll get there before the dead.
如果马能撑下去，
我们会赶在死人之前到达那里。
We just have to hope
the night king doesn't come first.
我们只能抱着希望
夜王不是第一位的。
Man: Keep moving! Straight up!
男：继续走！直!
Stay together! Don't fall behind!
呆在一起!不要落后！